

Nusret Ipek

PhD Bioscience Engineering: Mathematical Modelling



Naamsesteenweg 294 Bus 001, Heverlee, 3001



+32(0)474023634



https://kermit.ugent.be/ phd.php?author=N.%20Ipek



nusret.ipek@ugent.be

Objective –

PhD student in Bioscience Engineering with a strong background in statistics, data analysis and computer programming. My goal is to deepen my knowledge in machine learning and programming for animal welfare.

Skills -Julia R Python **AMPL QGIS** Java HTML & CSS C & C++ SAS ArcGIS **MATLAB**

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Accomplishments

- Awarded by Arizona State University called Moeur Award for exceptional academic achievement which is given to the students who are completed their degrees in 4 years with 4.00 GPA and it corresponds approximately top 1% of the students each year.
- Magna Cum Laude from KU Leuven ranking in top 5 out of 70 graduates.
- Graduated with honors of Summa Cum Laude recognized by ASU.

Education

Since 2021 University of Ghent (UGent)

PhD

Bioscience Engineering: Mathematical Modelling Concentrated in computer vision and machine learning

Working with caged farm animal videos.

2019-2021 KU LEUVEN MSc

Master of Science in Statistics and Data Science

Concentrated in European Master Official Statistics (EMOS)

Degree provided solid theoretical and practical background in the areas of machine learning, time-series, inference, statistical modelling and GIS.

2013-2017 ARIZONA STATE UNIVERSITY, TEMPE BSE

Engineering Management

Concentration in Business Analytics

4.00 GPA

Work Experience

2019-2021 **Euthority Project** TEXT MINING AND MACHINE LEARNING

Scrapping domestic and supranational court documents

Mining and applying machine learning algorithms on legal documents

Integrating state-of-art deep leaning models to the project

2017-2018 Ozel Fittings LTD PROJECT MANAGEMENT SPECIALIST

> Working on projects for increasing customer satisfaction Development of cost reductive solutions in distribution network

ASU Admission Services STUDENT WORKER 2013-2014

Worked with sensitive personal data

Worked directly with administration to help to solve problems Contacted and directed future students with phone and e-mail

Internship Projects

2020 Flemish Statistical Authority: VSA Data Specialist Intern

> Using big data from Flemish business websites and natural language processing techniques to create cost effective official statistic of innovation

2020 **EUROSTAT Coding Labs** Data Analyst Intern

> Building a spatial model to predict population distribution with mobile network operator data Application focused on Belgium.

2017 Treasures 4 Teachers, USA Student Intern

> Focused on system design improvements for a non-profit organization and used six-sigma methodology

Cortez Coffee Company, USA 2016 Student Intern

Implemented lean thinking system in coffee making process

Certificates

2017 Lean Green Belt Certificate 2017 Six Sigma Green Belt Certificate

Other information

Since 2019 Member of Royal Statistical Society